ATA BERK YILMAZ Backend Developer

+905380618284

• Istanbul

https://atayiilmaz.github.io/

in linkedin.com/in/ataberkyiilmaz

github.com/atayiilmaz

SUMMARY

Recent graduate with a degree in Computer Engineering. Completed internships at Teknasyon and Jotform. Background in web development with experience in both frontend and backend development. Actively involved as a member of the IEEE Student Branch Computer Society Technical Team. Worked with various technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and popular frameworks such as Node.js and Laravel.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Backend Development Intern

Jotform

2023/08 – 2023/09 Istanbul, Turkey

• Developed a REST API for the campaigns admin panel.

- Implemented efficient and secure endpoints, ensuring data integrity and scalability.
- Used skills: PHP, MySQL, Redis, Testing, RDS(remote development server), RestAPI.

Backend Development Intern

Teknasyon

2022/08 – 2022/09 Istanbul, Türkiye

- Built a RestAPI, MVC structure and learned about the design patterns.
- Used skills: PHP, MySQL, GitHub, Docker, RestAPIs.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering (%100 English)

Bandırma Onyedi Eylul University

2020/09 – 2024/06 Balıkesir, Turkey

Bachelor's Degree in Business Management

Istanbul University

• As a second university. (External Degree)

2021/09 – Present Istanbul, Turkey

2023/12 - 2024/06

ORGANIZATIONS

IEEE BANU Student Branch

Computer Society Technical Team Member

- Algo Sprint
- IEEE Banu Website

CERTIFICATES & AWARDS

IBM Cloud Essentials V3 🛮

Issued by IBM

CCNA: Introduction to Networks

Issued by Cisco

The Duke of Edinburgh International Award- Bronze Category

• Issued by DofE foundation.

SKILLS

Bash • Linux • Git • GitHub • GCP (Cloud Run, Cloud SQL) • Docker • PHP (Laravel) • Python • HTML/CSS • Javascript (Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js) • MySQL • PostgreSQL

LANGUAGES

English (Upper Intermediate) | **Spanish** (Beginner)

2022/00